while some athletes may want to Target a
specialty bar to match one specific
style of lifting multi-purpose bars like
the rep Fitness Colorado bar are
typically the way to go for most home
gym owners since they can be used across
all of your lifts this bar is available
in 20 and 15 kilograms it comes in two
different finishes the knurling is super
grippy and there's composite bushings in
the loading sleeves that provide a
really solid rate of spin it's one of my
favorite barbells on the market right
now so hang tight y'all we got a lot to
talk about today in this review
good
[Music]
what's up it's Jake back in the barbing
garage gym and for today's video I've
got the rep Fitness Colorado bar in for
review now if you don't know how this
whole process works in this video today
I'm going to tell you everything you
need to know about this bar we're going
to talk about the price we're going to
talk about some features and what it's
made of we're also going to talk about
some things I like and maybe might not
be too crazy about we're also going to
talk about who should or maybe should
not add this to their home gym now
pump the brakes for a second before I
start doing all that we've reviewed a
whole lot of barbells and barbin.com we
went ahead and made a best list of
everything that we've tested so if you
want to check that out all you got to do
is start barbing best barbells and you
can find out for yourself which ones we
like best
foreign
okay so let's talk about some pros and
cons with the rep Fitness Colorado bar I
think we got to talk about versatility
first when it comes to these Pros you
know versatility is a really important
feature in my opinion with all home gym
equipment and that's really you know
what is the main selling point with this
bar right here you know you can do all
of your lifts whether you're wanting to
power clean deadlift whatever it is you
can do that with this barbell and you
know that's going to save you money from
having to go and purchase you know a
power bar and an Olympic Bar speaking of
saving money you know this is actually
pretty competitively priced considering
the overall quality of it which is you
know obviously a really nice thing right
here now the knurling right here is
moderate which is nice as you're going
to do those power cleans hang cleans
clean and jerk whatever it is you're
wanting to do but it's also grippy
enough to where you know you don't feel
compromised as you're going to do your
deadlifts and your bench presses which
is Primo right there it's also available
in 20 and 15 kilograms and if you're
looking for you know a smaller lighter
bar definitely find that right there and
the composite bushings are here are
really nice in my opinion yes they
provide you know a really solid rate of
spin they're going to last you longer
than you know bronze or Brash brass
bushings will probably longer than some
bearings will as well but they're also
quieter especially compared to you know
the brass and bronze bushings whenever
you drop this bar one of the first
things I noticed was that it almost
sounded like a dead bounce which is a
nice thing right there especially if you
have neighbors that are in close
proximity of you and then when really
when it comes to those cons in my
opinion you know I just mentioned it is
competitively priced but you know
somebody who doesn't want to spend you
know over 300 bucks on a barbell you can
find some for 200 now I know it's only
100 120 bucks difference but that can
kind of free up a little bit of money
for you know weight bench maybe you know
adjustable kettlebell system or
dumbbells or some extra weight plates
really you know whatever it is that can
you know save you a little bit of money
and then also you know it's not going to
be the best that any one lift yeah you
can do it you can use it for all of them
but you know when it comes to people who
are a dedicated power lifter CrossFit or
Olympic lifter you're definitely going
to want to go after a specialty bar
foreign
so when it comes to money remember this
bar is available in 20 and 15 kilograms
and it comes in two different finishes
so let's talk about the 20 kilogram bar
first this hard Chrome version it's
going to run you right around 320 bucks
that cerakote version is going to be
around 330. that 15 kilogram bar the
hard crumbs around 270 and the Sarah
coat's about 280. shipping is free which
is something I think is really nice with
rep Fitness they do that with all their
stuff and that's just really nice you
don't have to pay extra money just to
get something delivered to you now when
it comes to you know comparing this bar
to the rest of the market honestly I
think this is a really solid price tag
in my opinion now I know I mentioned
just a minute ago that you can find a
barbell for about 100 bucks cheaper and
it kind of you know creates some more
wiggle room within your budget and add
more equipment to your home gym that's
still true you know if you need to do
that want to do that definitely go for
it but all honesty this is a really
solid price tag you know especially
compared to other similar bars on the
market this is really high quality and
to be honest with you I think rep could
be charging even more money for this bar
150 more if they wanted to so at the end
of the day
it's a really solid price tag
so let's talk about how rep constructed
this bar and I want to talk about the 20
kilogram bar first so it's going to be
86.6 inches long with 16 inch loading
sleeves and a diameter of 28 and a half
millimeters now with that 15 kilogram
bar that's going to be 79 inches long
with 12.4 inch loading sleeves and a 25
millimeter diameter all right so once
again you know it does come in this hard
Chrome which is you know more resistant
to rust and corrosion and standard
Chrome but you can also go for the
cerakote version which is going to be a
step above and that's something really
nice plus with that cerakote version it
has DuraCoat loading sleeves now just
you know a quick explanation of what
DuraCoat is it's basically a chemical
process that rep has been using and it's
gonna basically you know make the
sleeves more resilient to wear and tear
and corrosion and everything than this
chrome is basically it's going to make
it tougher in general which is a nice
thing that's a really nice thing right
there now regardless of which bar you go
for they're going to have a max weight
capacity you have 1500 pounds and a
tensile strength rating of 190 000 PSI
now 1500 pounds that's plenty I think
for pretty much every single athlete now
that tensile strength rating that is
really gonna you know come into effect
for you know people who are really
lifting Elite level numbers right so
tensile strength if you don't know it's
going to tell you how hard a barbell is
how much you know punishment it can
handle I guess I should say 190 000
that's gonna be plenty for most people
now like I said if you are lifting some
Elite crazy eye-popping numbers you
might want to go after something you
know the 210 to 230 range so definitely
keep that in mind now the knurling right
here is really nice in my opinion you
know especially considering it is hard
Chrome so typically you know a bar that
has you know some type of coating it's
going to be a little slippery compared
to a stainless steel bar I don't
consider that to be the case right here
I just have a really solid grip when I'm
doing all of my lifts you also have your
dual neural markings right here so if
you don't know what these are inner ones
are by you know International
powerlifting Federation outer ones
International weightlifting Federation
and that's really just going to help you
get you know that identical and ideal
hand placement for you know your
specific lifts with the loading sleeves
they are smooth now a lot of times with
multi-purpose bars you'll find a grooved
pattern right there and that's to help
keep those weight plates in their
original positioning you know when
especially whenever you're going to do
anyway any lift excuse me where you're
dropping the bar and it's going to
prevent those weights from sliding down
so since it doesn't have that you know
you're definitely going to want to toss
on some weight collars which you should
anyway is just for your own protection
and then you know with these composite
bushings I think that's a really nice
touch you know it gives you a really
solid rate of spin you know when you're
going to do those Olympic and Crossfit
style lifts but you know it's going to
last longer as well compared to bronzer
brass bushings but also you have the
really the main thing for me right here
is how quiet it is when you drop your
barbell and just hang tight I'm gonna
break that down in just a second
[Applause]
[Music]
all right so I just want to you know
highlight some things with this bar up
close for you guys we're going to start
with the end cap here and move our way
down the tension the detail right here
is just really nice
you know I think that's really cool we
get Colorado and state colors and
everything if you ever need to you know
take the loading sleeves off and
re-lubricate them or anything like that
snap Rings right here you can easily do
that it's a really nice touch now you
don't have any grooves on these loading
sleeves I personally don't have an issue
with that you know you're skipping out
on that zip noise whenever you load and
unload plates which can be pretty
annoying for some people but since you
don't have those grooves you know the
chances of your plates you know sliding
down the sleeves are definitely increase
so you definitely you know just want to
toss on some weight collars and you
should anyways now these composite
bushings are going to provide you know
really solid rate of spin it's not you
know it's not going to spend as much as
say you know an Olympic Bar that has you
know ball bearings
but that's okay with a bar like this
definitely gets the job done and you're
able to use it you know with your power
lifting movements as well now let's move
on a little further and I'm gonna step
in the rack here the grip is really nice
right here I don't know if you can you
can tell or not but you know we haven't
had this bar too terribly long I mean
it's it's a brand new barbell that rep
just came out with right so
it's really really relatively new and a
handful of uses whatever
you can actually see in here where you
know I've had some dead skin come off
that might be kind of gross but that
just shows you know how grippy this
barbell really is now it's not gonna
tear your hands up it's still pretty
moderate at the end of the day but
that's just a good Testament to you know
how good of a grip you're gonna get at
you know as you're working out and
obviously you know you do have your iwf
and ipf neural markings right here that
way you're able to get you know
identical hand placement and you know
everything like that now you don't have
a center neural right here you know
that's pretty much standard I guess you
could say with multi-purpose bars now
with a power lifting bar that's going to
have you know a pretty abrasive knurling
right here and that's to help keep that
barbell on your back whenever you're
going to do you know your back squats
sometimes with Olympic bars you'll have
you know a small very very light you
know cross hatching knurling pattern
right there just to help keep that bar
on your chest during those Olympic style
lifts that's not the case here you know
so you do miss out on a little bit of
grip but at the end of the day it's not
that bad and then I want to you know
show you guys these composite bushings
down here
and they honestly they're really nice so
the big thing here is that they're gonna
you know last longer than bronze or
brass bushings but they're also quieter
overall you know sometimes with barbells
you can kind of hear everything as it
spins I guess that makes sense but also
whenever you drop it this bar is a lot
quieter than some other ones so let's go
ahead and toss some light on here and
show you guys what I'm talking about all
right so I tossed some weight on here
really quick as I said this is just
gonna take a second I just want to kind
of give you guys you know my Impressions
with this bar so we're going to do a
hang clean really quick
that spin feels really nice
and I know it bounced all over the place
just then and you might not be able to
really tell but compared to other you
know multi-purpose bars and anything
that uses you know bushings it's
actually a little bit more of a dull
sound which is really nice and also
those composite bushings right there
they're really nice I got a really solid
spin with that bar because remember
whenever you're going to do any type of
lift like that the bar right here is
actually what's spinning you know and
not those sleeves so overall pretty
impressed all right now this barbell is
going to be great for anybody who's
looking for a competitively priced bar
it's also really high quality remember
it's about 320 bucks which is a pretty
solid deal in my opinion now also you
know designed to be the only barbell
that you need in your home gym so if
you're not wanting to you know purchase
multiple bars and save a little bit of
money that way you can incorporate power
lifting and Olympic style lifting you
can definitely do that with this bar
right here you know it's meant to be
that one bar jack of all trades bar it
can do it all and also you know if
you're looking for a smaller size
barbell remember this is also available
in 15 kilograms now on the flip side
really the only reason in my opinion
somebody may not want to purchase this
bar is because you know you're a
dedicated power lifter or you know an
Olympic CrossFit style lifter and you're
looking for a specialty bar that can
handle those specific style of lifts you
know this has characteristics traits
whatever you want to call it of both
styles of barbells which is why you can
do all of those lists but it's not going
to be the best at any one given lift
right so definitely just keep that in
mind
foreign
over the rep Fitness Colorado bar
remember if you're a dedicated lifter
you know on one end of the spectrum this
may not be the best option for you but
if you're looking for you know a bar
that can serve as the only one you need
in your home gym it's competitively
priced and it's really high quality I
think this is a really solid Contender
thanks for watching y'all hope this
video was really helpful and I was able
to tell you everything you need to know
about this barbell as always keep your
eyes peeled for my next video for now
head over to barbin.com because we have
a full written article about this
barbell I definitely think you should
check that out all you got to do is
search bar Bend rep Fitness Colorado Bar
review it's going to pull right up for
you you can go over all the details
every single thing we discussed here
today I'll catch y'all next time
[Music]
thank you